Guide to the Center for Policy Analysis records, 1987-2006.
Center for Policy Analysis records
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Center for Policy Analysis records, 1987-2006.
6755
Center for Policy Analysis, Washington, D.C.
7 cubic ft.
Printed Materials, Publications, Reports, Research Materials
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Records of the Center, including reports, pamphlets, brochures, and newsletters.
COLLECTION DESCRIPTION
Records of the Center, including reports, pamphlets, brochures, and newsletters.
SUBJECTS
Names:
Center for Policy Analysis, Washington, D.C.
Subjects:
City planning.
INFORMATION FOR USERS
NOTES
Forms part of Progressive Cities and Neighborhood Planning Collections.
CONTAINER LIST
- NYS Data Center Annual Report- Flemming Leadership Institute: Washington D.C.: Center for Policy Alternatives, 2006., November 28, 2006; Folder w/ Documents (Box 1, Folder 1)
  CPA History Timeline sheet: 1page; Flemming Leadership Institute's alumni interaction descriptions & congressmen members name by state: 5 pages; Flemming Leadership Institute phamphlet
- Alternatives- Newsletter of the Center for Policy Alternatives, 1993-1997., 1993-1997; Newsletter in Binder (Box 1, Folder 2)
  32 newsletter documents from 1993-1997 in binder; Yr1993: 5 newsletters; Yr1994: 6 newsletters; Yr1995: 6 newsletters; Yr1996: 6 newsletters; Yr1997: 9 newsletter
- Midwest Summit, June 29-30, 2001, Detroit, Michigan: Progressive Solutions for the Midwest- Connecting legislators with advocates and experts to develop progressive public policy agendas. Washington D.C.: Center for Policy Alternatives, 2001., June 29, 2001; Informational Binder (Box 1, Folder 3)
  Summit info binder: 10 sections including agenda, participant contact info, speaker bios, policy topics & legislation reviews, media strategies, about CPA section; Alternatives newsletter Summer 2001 Vol.9 No.3
- Ways & Means Newsletter. Washington D.C.: Center for Policy Alternatives, 1982-1993., 1982-1993; Newsletter in Binder (Box 1, Folder 4)
  Way & Means newsletter documents from 1982-1993 in binder: 47 newsletters total
- Alternatives- Newsletter of the Center for Policy Alternatives. Washington D.C., 1998-2001., 1998-2001; Newsletter in Binder (Box 1, Folder 5)
  28 newsletter documents from 1998-2001 in binder; Yr1998: 8 newsletters; Yr1999: 9 newsletters; Yr2000: 7 newsletters; Yr2001: 4 newsletters
- Western Training and Forum- Inside Strategies: Serving Effectively in Office. Portland, Oregon: Center for Policy Alternatives, 2001., August 5, 2001; Informational Binder (Box 1, Folder 6)
  Training & Forum info binder: 8 sections including agenda, participant contact info, speaker bios, policy topics & legislation reviews, about CPA section; policy issues survey & blank evaluation sheet
- The Flemming Fellows Leadership Institute. Washington D.C.: The Center for Policy Alternatives, 2002., January 2002; Informational Binder (Box 1, Folder 7)
  Retreat info binder: 8 sections including agenda, facilitator bios, member contact info, about CPA section; handwritten notes on looseleaf; Flemming Fellows 2002 class names, faciliator evaluations
- Southwest Regional Conference- A Forum for Progressive Action. San Antonio, Texas: Center for Policy Alternatives, 2002., July 12, 2002; Informational Binder (Box 1, Folder 8)
  Conference info binder: 5 sections including participant contact info, speaker bios, 3 policy issues, reform bills; agenda; policy issue checklist; blank evaluation; Alternatives newsletter Spring 2002 Vol.10 No.2
- Midwest Regional Conference- A Forum for Progressive Action. Milwaukee, Wisconsin: Center for Policy Alternatives, 2002., August 16, 2002; Informational Binder (Box 1, Folder 9)
  Conference info binder: 8 sections including participant contact info, speaker bios, media training, policy issues & legislation reviews; CPA "Plug into the network…" brochure; agenda, policy issue checklist; blank evaluation form; Alternatives newsletter Spring 2002 Vol.10 No.2
- Northeast Regional Conference - A Forum for Progressive Action. June 27-28. Sturbridge, Massachusetts: Center for Policy Alternatives, 2002., June 27, 2002; Informational Binder (Box 2, Folder 1)
  Conference info binder: 8 sections including participant contact info, speakers, sponsors, policy issues & reviews, policy toolkits; agenda, policy issue checklist; blank evaluation form; Alternatives newsletter Spring 2002 Vol.10 No.2
- Southeast Regional Conference - A Forum for Progressive Action. August 2-3. Tunica, Mississippi: Center for Policy Alternatives, 2002., August 2, 2002; Informational Binder (Box 2, Folder 2)
  Conference info binder: 8 sections including participant contact info, speakers, sponsors, policy issues & reviews; agenda, policy issue checklist; blank evaluation form
- Eleanor Roosevelt Global Leadership Institute - Domestic Retreat. May 30 - June 2. Washington D.C.: Center for Policy Alternatives, 2003., May 30, 2003; Informational Binder (Box 2, Folder 3)
  Retreat info binder: 5 sections including constituents & global issues review presentation, cross-cultural skills, local governance & trade, profile of China, class of 2003 info & faculty bios; CPA "Plug into the network..." brochure; agenda; blank evaluation form
- Women's Leadership Retreat 2003. June 6- 8. Philadelphia, Pennsylvania: Center for Policy Alternatives, 2003., June 6 2003; Informational Binder (Box 2, Folder 4)
  Retreat info binder: 5 sections including participant contact info, strategy sessions on women's health, caregiving, income security & economic opportunity; blank evaluation form; referral form; agenda; missing items: binder cover, CPA list, & speaker bios
- Northeast Regional Policy Leaders Forum - Progressive Policy Solutions for the Northeast. September 14-15. Braintree, Massachusetts: Center for Policy Alternatives, 2001., September 14, 2001; Informational Binder (Box 2, Folder 5)
  Forum info binder: 8 sections including participant contact info, policy review of election reform & economic security, issues workshops, messaging strategies, policy toolkits, sponsors; agenda, policy issues survey, blank evaluation form, Alternatives newsletter Spring 2001 Vol.9 No. 3
- Southwest Regional Policy Leaders Forum - Progressive Policy Solutions for the Southwest. July 27-28. Albuquerque, New Mexico: Center for Policy Alternatives, 2001., July 27, 2001; Informational Binder (Box 2, Folder 6)
  Forum info binder: 10 sections including participant contact info, speaker bios policy issues review, media strategies, about CPA section; agenda; news advisory; Consumers Union article; policy issues survey; blank evaluation form, Alternatives newsletter Spring 2001 Vol.9 No. 3
- Southeast Regional Policy Leaders Forum - Progressive Policy Solutions for the New South. July 20- 21. Atlanta, Georgia: Center for Policy Alternatives, 2001., July 20, 2001; Informational Binder (Box 2, Folder 7)
  Forum info binder: 10 sections including participant contact info, speaker bios, southern demographics, policy issues review, media strategies, about CPA section; agenda; policy issues survey; blank evaluation form; copy of Souther Changes newsletter Winter 200 Vol.22 No.4; Alternatives newsletter
- Grassroots Women Leadership Retreat. June 6-9. Lake Tahoe, Nevada: Center for Policy Alternatives, Nevada Women's Agenda & Nevada's Women's Lobby, Rockefeller Family Fund, 2002., June 6, 2002; Informational Binder (Box 2, Folder 8)
  Retreat info binder: 8 sections including program overview, participant contact info, policy issues review, tools & resources, sponsoring organizations
- Work & Family in the New Economy: Innovations in the States. October 5-6. San Francisco, CA: Center for Policy Alternatives, 2000., October 5, 2000; Informational Binder (Box 2, Folder 9)
  Conference info binder: 8 sections including agenda, speaker bios, participant contact info, policy issues review, about CPA section; keynote speech notes (2 copies); Remarks speech from Amy B. Dean for CPA; blank evaluation form; Alternatives newsletter Sept/Oct 2000 Vol.8 No.5
- Eleanor Roosevelt Global Leadership Institute - Domestic Retreat. April 20-23. The Pocantico Conference Center of the Rockefeller Brothers Fund: Center for Policy Alternatives, 2001., April 20, 2001; Informational Binder (Box 2, Folder 10)
  Retreat info binder: 8 sections including agenda, class of 2001 contact info, faculty bios, reference material, local governance & trade agreements, intro to Chile, action plan, section about CPA; blank evaluation form
- Eleanor Roosevelt Global Leadership Institute - Domestic Retreat. Washington D.C.: The Pocantico Conference Center of the Rockefeller Brothers Fund, Center for Policy Alternatives, 2002., July 19, 2002; Informational Binder (Box 2, Folder 11)
  Retreat info binder: 5 sections including constituents & global issues review presentation, cross-cultural skills, profile of Chile, class of 2002 info & faculty bios, community contact project, leadership coaching;agenda; blank evaluation form; retreat summary, Chile study tour sheet
- Various Authors. Federal Tax Reform and Implications for the State--Innovative Ideas for America's State and Local Governments. Washington, D.C.: National Center for Policy Alternatives, 1987., January 8, 1987, August 1987; Policy Report (Box 3, Folder 8)
  Two legislation reviews- 1#: Federal Tax Reform & Implications for the States: 22 pages (Written by Linda Tarr-Whelan & Robert McGarrah. January 8, 1987), 2#: Special State Legislative Report- Financial Institutions & Community Reinvestment: 33pages (Written by John Fellin. July 1987)
- A Citizen's Handbook on Jobs. Washington D.C.: Center for Policy Alternatives, National Committee for Full Employment, 1988., June 16, 1988; Photocopy of Policy Handbook (Box 3, Folder 9)
  Report for legislative actions on jobs in the U.S.- 3 sections including federal policy limitations, need for state action, model programs & case studies, reform alternatives: 50 pages
- Business Climate Yields to Growth Climate: The Midwest Pioneers the New Age- A Report for the Midwest Leadership Network of the National Center for Policy Alternatives (DRAFT). Washington D.C.: National Center for Policy Alternatives w/ Mt. Auburn Associates, 1987., May 1, 1987; Report (Draft) (Box 3, Folder 10)
  Summary of "business climate", 5 sections of myths, factors, state legislations, and alternatives for the business growth: 82 pages total
- Hamrin, Robert D.. Beyond Business Climate: Economic & Environmental Partnerships- Conference for Midwest Leaders. Milwaukee, Wisconsin: National Center for Policy Alternatives, 1987., October 11, 1987; Speech (Box 3, Folder 11)
  Comments by Robert D. Hamrin at the opening plenary of the conference: 14 pages total
- Tarr-Whelan, Linda. Progressive Federalism: A Model to Achieve Economic and Social Justice. Washington D.C.: Center for Policy Alternatives, 1989., January 9, 1989; Policy Report (Box 3, Folder 12)
  Concept paper on the background of progressive federalism and alternatives for new legislation: 8 pages
- Various Authors. Economic Initiatives- State Report. Innovative Ideas for America's State & Local Governments. Washington D.C.: National Center for Policy Alternatives, 1989,1991., December 1989, July 1991; Policy Report (Box 3, Folder 13)
  2 state reports on economic initiatives- #1: 4 sections by various authors- 45 pages (Edited by Robert K. Stunberg & Anne E. Hoskins. December 1989). #2: Photocopy of Special Report on Economic Conversion, 4 sections- 24 pages total (Edited by Anne E. Hoskins & Keith Cunningham); 1 summary paper on New Initiatives in Economic Conversion by Mark Graham- 3 pages
- Midwest Brief: Voter Registration Laws & Voter Turnout--Innovative Ideas for America's State & Local Government. Washington D.C.: National Center for Policy Alternatives, 1990., February 1990; Policy Report (Box 3, Folder 14)
  Draft legislative brief of voter laws & voter turnout- Case studies of 8 states, plus intro, conclusion, CPA info, and appendices: 52 pages total
- Various Authors. Policy Reports. Washington D.C.: Center for Policy Alternatives, 1990., Various; Policy Report (Box 3, Folder 15)
  June, September, November, December 1990. 4 policy reviews- #1: State Reinvestment Policy (Robert Stumberg. June 1990) summary and analysis of Community Reinvestment Act of 1977- 31 pages. #2: Leading The Way to a Diversified Economy (Anne E. Hoskins & Amy Haught. Sept.1990)- 11 pages. #3: Policy Options for Converting State Economies (Anne Hoskins & J.D. White. December 1990)- 8 pages. #4: Summary of Federal Legislation on Defense Economic Adjustment & Conversion for FY1991- 3 pages; conversion contacts & survey results
- Progressive Federalism: The States Lead, Washington Follows--National Progressive Policy Conference. Georgetown University Law Center, Washington, D.C.: Center for Policy Alternatives, 1990., December 4, 14-16, 1990; Conference Report (Box 3, Folder 16)
  Various Conference Materials: 1 CPA News Release- 2pages; 1 description summary of conference- 1page; photocopy of back side of summary- 1page; invitation letter to plenary speakers- 1 page; 1 grant letter for conference funding (by Linda Tarr-Whelan)- 2 pages; conference objectives (DRAFT)- 3 pages (numbered 8-10); conference overview- 7 pages; Final Report- 7pages
- Various Authors. Policy Reports & Legislative Analyses. Washington D.C.: Center for Policy Alternatives, 1991., January, March 5, May 2, July 1991; Policy Report (Box 3, Folder 17)
  4 Legislative reports & analyses- #1: Survey of State and Local Housing Trust Fund Programs- 38 pages (By: Anne E. Hoskins, Amy Haught, Sandra Green. January 1991). #2: CPA State Global Warming and Ozone Depletion Legislation- 1991 Legislative Year- 18 pages (March 5, 1991). #3: Resource Packet for Energy Efficiency Strategy Session- 36 pages (Various authors- articles. May 2, 1991). #4: Reinvesting in Communities: Policy Options for New Jersey- Executive Summary- 10 pages (By Anne E. Hoskins & Robert Stumberg frm CPA & Dan Hoffman & Richard Ferlauto frm American Affordable Housing Institute. July 1991).
- Various Authors. Policy Report & Legislative Analyses. Washington D.C.: Center for Policy Alternatives, 1992., May, November 23, & December 1992; Policy Report (Box 3, Folder 18)
  3 legislation materials- #1: State & Policy Support for Targeted Pension Fund Investment- 23 pages total (By Richard Ferlauto, Robert Stumberg, & Robin Sampson. May 1992). #2: Pensions & Investments- Funds fear Clinton pressure (2 photocopies of newspaper article by Joel Chernoff. Nov.23, 1992.) #3: Model Legislation Series- State Community Reinvestment Act- 14 pages total (By Robert Stumberg w/ Karen Valentine. December 1992.)
- Sementilli-Dann, Lisa, Solomon, Deborah, & Tso, Kim. Investing in Families: The Foundation for the New Economy (DRAFT). Washington D.C.: Center for Policy Alternatives, 1993., January 1993; Policy Report (Box 3, Folder 19)
  acknowledgements w/ contributors names; summary desciption for the creation of a legislative family agenda; 7 sections including intro, economic equity for caregivers, workplace flexibility, child care, child support, eldercare, conclusion; plus appendix & bibliography- 58 pages total
- Ryan, William & Schrader, Richard. An Ounce of Toxic Pollution Preventio: State Toxics Use Reduction Laws - Second Edition. Washington D.C.: National Environmental Law Center & Center for Policy Alternatives, 1993., January 1993; Policy Report (Box 3, Folder 20)
  8 sections including executive summary, intro, background on toxins, needs for toxin reduction, state laws evaluations, funding for pollution prevention laws, reform for toxics use reduction law; plus appendices & tables- 74 pages total; also written w/ Mike Derezin & Richard Regan
- Various Authors. Policy Reports & Legislative Analyses. Washington D.C.: Center for Policy Alternatives, 1993., February 17, April 13, May 19, 1993; Policy Report (Box 3, Folder 21)
  5 policy summaries & legislative analyses- #1: Model Legislation Series- Targeted Investment Act- 8 pages (By Duan Phillips & Richard Ferlauto. February 17, 1993). #2: CPA's Economic Development and Community Investment Package- 75 pages total- 5 sections (1993-1994). #3: Reinventing Block Grants: The Small Cities Community Development Block Grant (DRAFT)- 2 Photocopies- 6 pages each- odd#pgs missing (By Carter Lawson & Robert Stumberg w/ Lisa Fowler, Larry Calvert, & Karen Shiff. April 13, 1993). #4: Inclusive Job Training- Working w/ the Job Training Partnership Act to Promote Microenterprise Training- 24 pages total, some pages missing (By Tracey L. Kitzman. April 1993). #5: Inclusive Job Training- Using JTPA Funds for Microenterprise Training (Working DRAFT)- 35 pages total (By Tracey Kitzman. May 19, 1993)
- Cook, Scott. Economic Conversion Policy Alternatives - A Survey of 10 States. Washington D.C.: Center for Policy Alternatives, 1993., April 26, 1993; Policy Report (Box 3, Folder 22)
  Documented results of economic surveys from 10 states: California, Connecticut, Maine, Maryland, Massachusetts, Missouri, New York, Texas, Virginia & Washington. "The purpose of survey is to give an overview of policy alternatives state governments, legislators, and non-governmental organizations can undertake to address current defense budget cuts". - 28 pages
- Canegata, Gizette L. & Stumberg, Bob. Incentive Deposit Programs: A Detailed Summary and Comparative Analysis. Washington D.C.: Center for Policy Alternatives,1993., May 1993; Policy Report (Box 3, Folder 23)
  2 Photocopies of each packet- 30 pages each
- Stumberg, Robert w/ Fowler, Lisa, Calvert, Lawrence, & Sampson, Robin. Community Capital Builders - A Leadership Brief on Rural Intermediaries. Washington D.C.: Center for Policy Alternatives, 1993., May 1993; Policy Brief (Box 3, Folder 24)
  Brief on rural intermediaries including contents on rural development that works, support states, resource publications & organizations, etc. - 12 pages (2 orginal prints)
- Various Authors. Health Care Legislative Reports & Survey Studies. Washington D.C.: Center for Policy Alternatives, 1993., June 7, December 15, 1993; Policy Report (Box 3, Folder 25)
  4 legislative analysis & summary reports on health care - #1: The Child Care Credit Crunch- A Survey for Child Care Facilities - 20 pages (By Richard Ferlauto, Chris Owen & Deborah Solomon. June 1993). #2: Child Care Loan Guarantee Funds- 16 pages (By Thomas Shimkin. June 7, 1993). #3: Structuring a Paid Family and Medical Leave Bill For States to Avoid Preemption Under Erisa - 30 pages (By Stacey S. Shibao frm Harrison Institute State Legislation Clinic. Dec. 15.1993.)
- Ferlauto, Richard & Clabourn, Jeffrey. Economically Targeted Investments By State-Wide Public Pension Funds. Washington D.C.: Center for Policy Alternatives, 1993., September 1993; Policy Report (Box 3, Folder 26)
  Display copy of report; 9 sections including intro, emerging trends in state-wide ETI programs, defining & ETI categories, expanding & discontinued programs, best practices & state experiences, plus national funds, bibliographym appendices A & B- 58 pages total
- Seminar Reports, Agenda, Strategies, & Media Documents on the Radical Right. Washington D.C.: Center for Policy Alternatives, 1993., May, July, October 1993; Policy Report (Box 3, Folder 27)
  5 radical right related materials - #1: The Center for Policy Alternatives Focuses on the Radical Right - 7 pages (May 1993). #2: State Elected Leaders Address the Radical Right Challenge: Center for Policy Alternatives Seminar at the National Conference of State Legislatures - 8 pages (July 1993). #3: A Primer on the Radical Right: Agenda for an Alternative Response - 6 pages (October 1993). #4: State Strategies to Counter the Right - From the Center for Policy Alternatives - 6 pages (Date Unknown). #5: The Media Documents The Right: Recent Articles on the Radical Right - 8 newspaper articles -16 pages total (Various Authors. Nov/Dec 1992- July/Aug 1993)
- Cunningham, William Michael, Ferlauto, Richard, Gaddy, Robert Scott, Reyes Gavilan, Adelina, Green, James, Koch, Erna, Stumberg, Robert. Reinvesting Minbanc- Options Paper: Prepared for the Minbanc Capital Corporation Board of Directors. Washington D.C.: Center for Policy Alternatives, 1993., October 13, 1993; Policy Report (Box 3, Folder 28)
  Description summary of alternatives for regulatory changes in supporting the capital needs of minority-owned banks; executive summary; 4 sections including intro, capital, capacity, & conclusion - 29 pages total
- Economically Targeted Investments: Rebuilding America's Communities & Health Care Proposal. Washington D.C.: Center for Policy Alternatives, 1994., February 9-11, 17, 1994; Policy Report (Box 3, Folder 29)
  3 Policy Reports/ Proposals- #1: Economically Targeted Investments: Rebuilding America's Communities - CPA Conference Report - 16 pages (Various Authors- Feb.9-11, 1994). #2: Economically Targeted Investments: Rebuilding America's Communities - A National Conference - 5 pages; photocopy of conference info packet (Feb. 9-11, 1994). #3: Helping Workers Balance Work and Family: Options for Paid Family and Medical Leave - 41 pages, 6 sections
- Various Authors. Alternative Options for Sustainable Development, Financing Agriculture, & Telecommunications. Washington, D.C.: Center for Policy Alternatives, 1994., June 24-25, 1994; Policy Brief (Box 3, Folder 30)
  3 legislation proposals & update for a better living - #1: Using Federal Data for Sustainable Development - 24 pages total (By Richard Civille & Jeff Tryens. June 1994. CPA & Center for Civic Networking). #2: Financing Alternative Agriculture: Model State Initiatives for Financing Conversion to Alternative Agricultural Practices- 16 pages total (By Timothy Boller. June 1994). #3: Update on Telecommunications Legislation in the Midwest, 1994 - 7 pages total (By The Yahara Center in Madison, Wisconsin. Sponsored by CPA & Center for Civic Networking. June 24-25, 1994).
- Liu, Kenneth & Park, Angela. Feebates: An Action Guide For States. Washington D.C.: Center for Policy Alternatives, 1994., May 1984; Policy Report (Box 3, Folder 31)
  Policy review book on feedbates. Sections include feedbates overview, environmental & economic impacts, organizing campaign, fact sheet, list of experts, analysis of proposed programs & state legislation
- Tryens, Jeffrey. Unfunded Mandates: Clarifying The Debate. Washington D.C.: Center for Policy Alternatives, 1994., July 1994; Policy Report (Box 3, Folder 32)
  Policy review book on unfunded mandates. Sections include executive summary, state & local problem, conservative agenda, studies, "guesstimates", solutions
- Smith, Burck, Kennedy, John & Ewing, Rebecca. Implementation of the National Voter Registration Act: A Status Report. Washington D.C.: Center for Policy Alternatives, 1994., July 1994; Policy Report (Box 3, Folder 33)
  Policy report on the National Voter Registration Act. 5 sections including intro, major elements of the NVRA, implementation issues, NVRA legislation in the States & Implementation cost chart
- Community Capital Builders - A Leadership Brief on Rural Intermediaries. Washington D.C.: Center for Policy Alternatives, 1993., May 5, 1995; Concept Paper (Box 3, Folder 34)
  Concept paper on capital network & teleconference written for discussion & comment. 6 sections including summary, intro, need for proposal, desired results, proposed activities & roles of participating organizations
- Graham, Andrew. International Progressive Policy Conference on Wage Inequality. Easton, Maryland: various organizations, 1995., October 14-17, 1995; Conference Report (Box 3, Folder 35)
  Conference report on wage inequality. 4 sections. Participant contact info